https://www.ethicalhackx.com/crunch-generate-password-word-list-brute-force/


Ex1 - Create a passlist using crunch
creating passlist:
crunch 1 8 abcde123 >>pass.txt    


will create a pass list of 8 chars combinations from 
the text you have entered


crunch 4 4 -t 05%% >> ad.txt
הפקודה הזו תיצור קובץ סיסמאות אשר שני התווים
  
הראשונים שלו יהיו באופן קבוע 05 ושאר התווים יהיו רנדומליים
מבחינה מספרית

-t will create a phrase that contains special noted such as the following:

@@@@ - lowercase אותיות קטנות
,,,,, -highercase אותיות גדולות
%%%% - numeric מספרים
^^^^^ - special תווים מיוחדים

-z zips the file (winrar) (you must specifi -o to make it work 
-z bzip2/gzip

-o output : worldlist.txt
-i inverts from end to start
from aab to baa


*****************options**************************
-b Maximum bytes to write per file, so using this option the wordlist to be created can be split into various sizes such as KB / MB / GB (must be used in combination with "-o START" switch)
-c Number of lines to write to output file, must be used together with "-o START"
-d Limits the number of consecutive identical characters
-e Specifies when crunch should stop early
-f Path to the charset.lst file to use, standard location is '/pentest/passwords/crunch/charset.lst to be used in conjunction with the name of the desired charset list, such as 'mixalpha-numeric-space'
-i Inverts the output sequence from left-to-right to right-to-left (So instead of aaa, aab, aac, aad etc, output would be aaa baa caa daa)
-l When specifying custom patterns with the -t option, the -l switch allows you to identify which of the characters should be taken as a literal character instead of a place holder ( @,%^ )
-o Allows you to specify the file name / location for the output, e.g. /media/flashdrive/wordlist.txt
-p Prints permutations of the words or characters provided in the command line.
-q Prints permutation of the words or characters found in a specified file
-r Resumes from a previous session, exact same syntax to be used followed by -r
-s Allows you to specify the starting string for your wordlist.
-t Allows you to specify a specific pattern to use. Probably one of the most important functions!
Place holders for fixed character sets are ;
@ - Lower case alpha characters
, - Upper case alhpa characters
% - Numeric characters
^ - Special characters (including space)
-u - Supresses the output of wordlist size & linecount prior starting wordlist generation.
-z Adds support to compress the generation output, supports gzip, bzip & lzma